Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 106 in this exercise, we are going to implement
this kestrels algorithm in Java and we will discuss it's complex.
So we go to the source for the algorithm and we create the new Java class and I will name it as the
guest.
I like them.
Just name their guest.
Yes.
So this is the algorithm.
So before we start, we can download all of these source codes that we have created in the previous
videos from the Resources folder under each exercise on Udemy course.
So we start by making a public public static void, Dijkstra and we take into the parameter.
The graph, as I told you in the previous video and the source that we have implemented.
See?
OK.
So.
The graph that you need to apply this gets thrown in and the sauce, the sauce element or the sauce
point that you need to start from it.
OK, then now it's a very simple.
We start by making the count equal to graph dot length.
Now Boolean array is the is.
It's called visited
vertex equal to new Boolean and it is of length count.
So this boolean visited the vertex would be acting as like a checking if we have visited this element
before or not.
If we have visited this element, we need no need to re pass on it.
We don't need to pass through it again.
OK.
So I will create also and array called distance equal to you
and count.
We start by making for loop starting from i.e. equal to zero
I and less than count and I gloss plus
visited.
We made we mark the visited vertex for all the elements is equal to false.
We start internalizing it with false and distance at index ie equal to infinity, which is integer dot
maximum value
f.
So this is initializing with the elements or the vertices vertices, two zero two false or not, physical
or not.
Okay, this is the first step.
Now the second step is this dance of self loop is here.
So, yeah, I like the comments because if you need to review the code what you have made, use it,
look at the code and see the steps.
Fatuma distance of self load is easier distance at index source equal to zero, four and equal to zero
i less than count and I glass glass.
Then what we do, we need to go through all the elements.
Stuck.
Check and update, third step is update the distance.
Between neighboring vertices and the source
and source, so into equal to find minimum distance, we will create this method later on like this.
So that's the best distance and the visit that vertex this will find and the distance between neighboring
vertex and the source.
And we make the first visited Vertex the truth.
So we have visited this vertex.
So I will make the visit that vertex at the end.
You said you, which will be returning is equal to true.
No.
The fourth step is updating our update to all the neighboring vertex distances Ford and V equal to zero.
If you if you go back to the animation, you can find very good explanation about this algorithm.
So if you don't understand it, please go back and return later to this coding.
OK.
No, we need to check that we have two conditions to be true.
We need to check if it is the minimum distance and we need to check that.
We thought we don't visit this vertex before.
So do basic and very important algorithms that the and sort of conditions that we need to check if it
is the minimum distance and we need to check if we have visited this vertex or not.
So we check if it is not fair.
Is it that Vertex at Index V and the graph at Index U?
This is an additional this is an additional condition U and V that we need to check.
If this does not equal to zero, you can.
You can add it.
This is good to add this third condition, but with that we need to check if there's not visited and
if it is the minimum distance between.
The vertex that you are on and the vertex that you are going to move to it.
So distance at index you plus graph that index, you will see less than that distance at the index fee.
So you can visit.
OK.
So we are checking if it is not less than that, visit that.
It is not the visit that revisited Vertex.
We are checking it for that graph at Index U and V is not equal to zero that we are going to move it
and the distance from you.
Plus the graph you did with this is the cost is less than the distance.
So what we will do, we are going to go through it and make the distance here,
the distance at index fee equal to distance at index you and plus a graph at Index U and V.
OK.
This is the condition for updating all the neighboring vertex distances.
No, that's a check here.
For a let's make a for loop that prints all the distances so aren't equal because, you know, I less
than distance focal length and I blast glass.
What we will do, we will make system that allows that print Allen drink.
The format, the distance from
this is I will use this syntax now like that and see language.
So the distance from S is percentage as.
What are the variables that we are going to implement from the system as from past two as three elements,
three variables that we mean as the first one is the source that we are going to throw to move from
it to the eye that we are going to move to and the distance that we are at coasting it.
What is the cost of the distance?
OK, so this is the algorithm.
Now we need to implement one more method before we start testing our our program.
So I will need to make a find the minimum distance I will click here.
Helpless enter.
Create the find method, find minimum, the minimum distance parameter, minimum distance and the Boolean.
Visit the first X.
OK.
No.
And minimum distance equal to an integer the maximum value.
And minimum distance
vertex equals to minus one for
sorry, you and I equal to zero I.
Less than distance dot length.
And I a plus plus we need to check if it is a visited or not.
So again, if does not equal to visit the Vertex index on this another visit and you see the end condition.
So this condition will be true and this condition would be true in order to execute this f.
So distance at index is less than minimum,
then what to do?
A minimum distance equal to distance at the index I and the minimum distance at vertex equal to high
return.
Minimum distance vertex.
OK,
so.
Let's move to the main method.
Create public static void main.
The president is throwing our eggs and we start Intergraph.
I will post a video and paste and write the code for the graphic in order to save that time.
So this is the graph that we have created as to the outrage that arrays array of arrays.
I want from you to post the video and think what these numbers represent in the graph.
These are the graph by itself, but I want from you to draw this like on paint, on or on note.
One note, one note or any program that you see.
And please comment it below in the comments below by by uploading this picture in order to see if you
understand the graph completely or not.
And we will see later on in the week and examples later and in the exercise that we are going to solve
by real examples and real real interview questions and real exams.
University exams, OK.
So
what I am doing here promoting this, this Castro, that we need to pass a graph and the starting source
point is equal to see.
OK, that's around this shastra.
And here we go, the distance from zero two zero zero, this distance from zero to one is three.
So we are moving this time from zero to two is one two zero two three is two zero two four four and
so on.
So this is that algorithm of this orchestra like finding the shortest path in social.
What are the application of the orchestra's algorithm?
You can see the orchestra's algorithm in many things in your Google map to find the shortest path in
social networking application, in telephone network and to find the locations in that map.
What is the Dish Orchestra's algorithm complexity?
So let's talk about complexity,
OK?
A complexity in terms of time, it would be time.
It would be all to be loug v
where e is that number of edges, be it a present at just the number and V represent the number of vertices
first two seasons
know the space complexity of this algorithm.
Space
would be all too vague because every vertex worries over the memory and it's sort of a part of memory
reserve a space in their memory so as the number of vertices increase the space complexity of this.